Guide to the Rachel Carson Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1921-79; Series I; 44; (101 boxes)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Articles and Essays
      - "Bear River: A National Wildlife Refuge." With Vanez T. Wilson. U. S. Department of the Interior: Fish and Wildlife Service brochure, 1950 (Box 95, Folder 1677)
      - "Biological Sciences"
        - Notes and references (Box 95, Folder 1678)
        - Typescripts and carbons (Box 95, Folder 1679-80)
        - Good Reading, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1681)
        - Related correspondence, 1955-60 (Box 95, Folder 1682)
      - "Bird Banding Is Their Hobby"
        - Research material and notes, 1932-49, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1683)
        - Drafts: typescripts and carbons, 1945, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1684-85)
        - Related correspondence, 1945-44 (Box 95, Folder 1686)
      - "Bird Man of Cape Cod"
        See: "Dr. Austin and the Cities of the Terns"
      - "Chesapeake Eels Seek the Sargasso Sea"
        - Baltimore Sun, 1938 Oct 9 (Box 95, Folder 1687)
      - "Chesapeake Oystermen See Stars"
        - Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1937 Mar 28 (Box 95, Folder 1688)
      - "Chincoteague: A National Wildlife Refuge." U. S. Department of the Interior: Fish and Wildlife Service. "Conservation in Action," Number One, 1947 (Box 95, Folder 1689)
      - "Clouds"
        - Research material, 1955, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1690)
        - Notes, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1691)
        - Typescripts, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1692-94)
        - "Something About the Sky." Omnibus: typescript, 1956 Mar 11 (Box 95, Folder 1695)
        - Related correspondence, 1956 (Box 95, Folder 1696)
      - "Debussy: La Mer" (Commentary)
        - Typescript, corrected, 1951 (Box 96, Folder 1697)
        - Page proofs, 1951 (Box 96, Folder 1698)
        - Printed copy, 1951 (Box 96, Folder 1699)
        - Promotional material, 1951 (Box 96, Folder 1700)
        - Related correspondence, 1951 Jul 13 (Box 96, Folder 1701)
      - "Dr. Austin and the Cities of the Terns"
        - Synopsis: typescript, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1702)
        - Draft A: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1703)
        - Draft B: typescript and carbon (Box 96, Folder 1704)
        - Related correspondence, 1945-46 (Box 96, Folder 1705)
      - "Ducks Are On Increase, But the Short Hunting Season Will Continue"
        - Typescript ("The Ducks Are Coming Back"), [1938] (Box 96, Folder 1706)
        - Baltimore Sun, 1938 Jan 16 (Box 96, Folder 1707)
      - ["The Exceeding Beauty of the Earth"]. "Words to Live By." This Week Magazine: typescript, 1951 (Box 96, Folder 1708)
      - "Farming Under the Chesapeake." Baltimore Sun, 1937 Jan 24 (Box 96, Folder 1709)
      - "Fight for Wildlife Pushes Ahead." Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1938 Mar 20 (Box 96, Folder 1710)
      - "Fish and Shellfish of the Middle Atlantic Coast." U. S. Department of the Interior: Conservation Bulletin Number 38, 1945 (Box 96, Folder 1711)
      - "Fish and Shellfish of the South Atlantic and Gulf Coasts." U. S. Department of the Interior: Conservation Bulletin Number 37, 1944 (Box 96, Folder 1712)
      - "Fishes of the Middle West." U. S. Department of the Interior: Conservation Bulletin Number 34, 1943 (Box 96, Folder 1713)
      - "Food from the Sea: Fish and Shellfish of New England." U. S. Department of the Interior: Conservation Bulletin Number 33, 1943 (Box 96, Folder 1714)
      - "Giants of the Tide-Rip"
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1715)
        - Baltimore Sun, 1938 Aug 28 (Box 96, Folder 1716)
      - "The Great Red-Tide Mystery"
        - Research material, 1947, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1717)
        - Draft A: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1718)
        - Draft B: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1719)
        - Draft C ("Killer from the Sea"): typescript, corrected, 1947 (Box 96, Folder 1720)
        - Field and Stream, 1948 Feb (Box 96, Folder 1721-22)
        - Related correspondence, 1947 (Box 96, Folder 1723)
      - "The Harbor." Falmouth Enterprise, 1952 May 16 (Box 96, Folder 1724)
      - "Housing of Starlings: Baltimore's Perennial Problem"
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1725)
        - Baltimore Sun ("Starlings a Housing Problem"), 1939 Mar 5 (Box 96, Folder 1726)
      - "How About Citizenship Papers for the Starling?" Nature Magazine, 1939 Jun-Jul (Box 96, Folder 1727)
      - "Indoor Ocean." This Month, 1946 Jun (Box 96, Folder 1728)
      - "An Island I Remember"
        - Notes: holograph, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1729)
        - Early drafts: typescripts, corrected, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1730)
        - Late draft: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1731)
      - "It'll Be Shad-Time Soon." Baltimore Sun, 1936 Mar 1 (Box 96, Folder 1732)
      - "It's Open Season for Oysters"
        - Typescript, [1938] (Box 96, Folder 1733)
        - Baltimore Sun ("Walrus and Carpenter Not Oysters Only Foe"), 1938 Aug 21 (Box 96, Folder 1734)
      - "The Land Around Us." New York Herald-Tribune, 1952 May 25 (Box 96, Folder 1735)
      - "Lifesaving Weed"
        - Notes and photos (Box 96, Folder 1736)
        - Typescript, [1944] (Box 96, Folder 1737)
      - "Long-Range Bird Migration"
        - Research material, 1945-48 (Box 97, Folder 1738)
        - Notes, 1948, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1739)
        - Early drafts, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1740)
        - Later draft (submitted to Holiday ), 1948 (Box 97, Folder 1741)
      - "Lost Worlds." The Wood Thrush, 1949 May-Jun (Box 97, Folder 1742)
      - "Make Spring Sing"
        - Typescript, 1963 Spr (Box 97, Folder 1743)
        - The News (Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania), 1963 Mar (Box 97, Folder 1744)
      - "Man's Great Peril--Pesticide Poisons." Chicago Sun-Times, 1963 May 26 (Box 97, Folder 1745)
      - Maryland Trout Culture Goes Modern": typescript, [1939] (Box 97, Folder 1746)
      - "Mass Production for Diamond-Back Terrapin"
        - Typescript ("Terrapin Farm Achieves Large Scale Production"), [1938] (Box 97, Folder 1747)
        - Baltimore Sun, 1938 Sep 13 (Box 97, Folder 1748)
      - "Mattamuskeet: A National Wildlife Refuge." U. S. Department of the Interior: "Conservation in Action," Bulletin Number Four, 1947 (Box 97, Folder 1749)
      - "La Mer"
        See: "Debussy: La Mer"
      - "Mr. Day's Dismissal." Reader's Digest, 1953 Aug (Box 97, Folder 1750)
      - "Mother of Life." In "The Living Ocean." The 1963 World Book Year Book (Special Report)
        - Early drafts ("The Sea"): holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 97, Folder 1751)
        - Revised typescript, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1752)
        - Printed copy, 1963 (Box 97, Folder 1753)
      - "The Moving Tides." Free World, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1754)
      - "A New Trout Crop for Anglers." Baltimore Sun, 1939 Apr 2 (Box 97, Folder 1755)
      - "The Northern Trawlers Move South"
        - Typescript ("A New Industry on Maryland's Horizon") (Box 97, Folder 1756)
        - Baltimore Sun, 1937 Jan 3 (Box 97, Folder 1757)
      - "Notes by Roger Christie at Pratt's Island, April 21, 1960": typescript (Box 97, Folder 1758)
      - "Numbering the Fish of the Sea." Baltimore Sun, 1936 May 24 (Box 97, Folder 1759)
      - "Ocean Resources"
        - Research material, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1760)
        - World Book Encyclopedia: typesetting copy, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1761)
        - Related correspondence, 1962 (Box 97, Folder 1762)
      - "Ocean Wonderland"
        - Notes, 1938, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1763)
        - Typescript, 1944 (Box 97, Folder 1764)
        - Transatlantic, 1945 Apr (Box 97, Folder 1765)
        - Related correspondence, 1944 (Box 97, Folder 1766)
      - "Of Man and the Stream of Time." Scripps College Bulletin, 1962 Jul (Box 97, Folder 1767)
      - "Our Ever-Changing Shore"
        - Notes, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1768)
        - Early drafts: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1769-70)
        - Later drafts: typescript, [1958] (Box 97, Folder 1771)
        - Holiday
          See: Oversize, Box 117, folder 2217
        - Related correspondence, 1958 (Box 97, Folder 1772)
      - "Oyster Dinners at Bottom of Chesapeake"
        - Richmond Times-Dispatch, 1937 Apr 25 (Box 97, Folder 1773)
      - "Parker River: A Natural Wildlife Refuge"
        - Notes ("Survey: September 18 to October 3, 1946") (Box 97, Folder 1774)
        - U. S. Department of the Interior: "Conservation in Action," Number Two, 1947 (Box 97, Folder 1775)
      - "Parker River: A New England Conservation Project"
        - The Bulletin of the Massachusetts Audubon Society (Reprint), 1947 (Box 97, Folder 1776)
      - "Poetry and the Sea": holograph and typescript, [1951] (Box 97, Folder 1777)
      - "Rachel Carson Answers Her Critics." The New England, 1963 Apr (Box 97, Folder 1778)
      - "Road of the Hawks"
        - Notes, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1779)
        - Early draft: holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1780)
        - Early drafts: typescripts, corrected, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1781)
        - Later draft: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1782)
        - Revised draft: typescript, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1783)
      - "Science Keeps Watch Over the Herds of the Sea": typescript, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1784)
      - The Sea (McGibbon and Kee). Introduction: holograph, 1963 (Box 98, Folder 1785)
      - "The Sea." In Our Natural Resources: A Study Guide Prepared by the Garden Club of America
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1786)
        - Our Natural Resources: A Study Guide: typescript, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1787)
        - Related correspondence, 1952 (Box 98, Folder 1788)
      - "The Sea"
        - The Johns Hopkins Magazine, 1961 May-Jun (Box 98, Folder 1789)
        - Related correspondence, 1960-61 (Box 98, Folder 1790)
      - "Sentiment Plays No Part in Save-the-Shad Movement"
        - Providence Journal, 1937 Feb 28 (Box 98, Folder 1791)
      - "Shad Catches Declining as the 1939 Season Opens"
        - Typescript ("Shad Supplies Still Declining"), n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1792)
        - Baltimore Sun, 1939 Mar 26 (Box 98, Folder 1793)
      - "Shad Going Way of the Buffalo." Charleston [S.C.] News and Courier, 1937 Feb 14 (Box 98, Folder 1794)
      - "Shallow Waters"
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1795)
        - Cape Cod Compass, 1953 (Box 98, Folder 1796)
      - [Empty folder] (Box 98, Folder 1797)
      - "She Started It All--Here's Her Reaction" [on federal pesticide report]. New York Herald-Tribune, 1963 May 19 (Box 98, Folder 1798-99)
      - "Sky Dwellers"
        See: "Ace of Nature's Aviators"
      - "Summer Time is Tick Time": typescript, 1937 (Box 98, Folder 1800)
      - "A Treasure Chest of Favorite Sea Books"
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1801)
        - The Washington Post, 1951 Dec 2 (Box 98, Folder 1802)
        - The Lookout ("Sea Chest of Stories"), 1952 Mar (Box 98, Folder 1803)
        - Related correspondence, 1951 (Box 98, Folder 1804)
      - "Undersea"
        - Early drafts, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1805-06)
        - Later draft, [1936] (Box 98, Folder 1807)
        - The Atlantic, 1937 Sep (Box 98, Folder 1808)
        - Falmouth [Mass.] Enterprise (Reprint), 1964 May 22 (Box 98, Folder 1809)
        - Related correspondence, 1936 (Box 98, Folder 1810)
      - "Undersea Sabateur"
        - Notes, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1811)
        - Various drafts, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1812)
      - "Whales and Whalers Gather in the Antarctic"
        - Typescript, [1938] (Box 98, Folder 1813)
        - Baltimore Sun ("Whalers Ready for New Season"), 1938 Nov 20 (Box 98, Folder 1814)
      - "Why America's Natural Resources Must Be Conserved"
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1815)
        - Outdoor Life, 1946 Jan (Box 98, Folder 1816)
      - "The World of Waters"
        See: "Undersea", Box 98 folder 1805
      - Untitled articles
        - Holy Trinity High School publication: typescript, 1961 (Box 98, Folder 1817)
        - New York Herald-Tribune Book Review article, 1951 Oct 7 (Box 98, Folder 1818)
        - New York Times article, [1962] (Box 98, Folder 1819)
        - Article for "Perpetuating Your Love for the Sea" (Woods Oceanographic Institute publication), 1954 Mar 18 (Box 98, Folder 1820)
        - Pesticide article: typescript, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1821)
        - [Wasp Invasion of the Pacific]: drafts, A and B, typescript, [1948] (Box 98, Folder 1822)
      - Letters to Editors, 1959-62 (Box 98, Folder 1823)
      - Miscellaneous fragments, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1824)
    - Book reviews
      - Typescripts and printed copies, 1938-62 (Box 99, Folder 1825)
      - Related correspondence, 1954-64 (Box 99, Folder 1826)
    - Speeches
      - AAAS General Symposium: The Sea Frontier
        - "The Edge of the Sea": typescript, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1827)
        - Related correspondence, 1953 Dec (Box 99, Folder 1828)
      - AAUW Speech (Virginia chapter): typescript, 1959 Dec 8 (Box 99, Folder 1829)
      - AAUW Achievement Award
        - Press releases, 1956 Jun (Box 99, Folder 1830)
        - Typescripts, 1956 (Box 99, Folder 1831-32)
        - Related correspondence, 1956 (Box 99, Folder 1833)
      - AAUW (Social and Economic Issues Committee Conference): synopsis and analysis, 1962 Sep (Box 99, Folder 1834)
      - American Geographical Society (Cullum Medal Acceptance): holograph and typescript, 1963 Dec 5 (Box 99, Folder 1835)
      - Associated Clubs of Virginia for Roadside Development: newspaper excerpts, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1836)
      - Audubon, Ornithological, and Natural History Societies: printed version, 1959 (Box 99, Folder 1837)
      - Audubon Society (1954 Dec 13)
        - Early drafts (slide lecture notes): holograph and typescript (Box 99, Folder 1838-39)
        - Later drafts: typescripts, corrected, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1840-42)
        - Lectern notes: photocopy, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1843)
        - Lectern copy: typescript, 1954 (Box 99, Folder 1844)
      - Audubon Society (1962 Oct 5) (Box 99, Folder 1845)
        - Typescript and photocopy (Box 99, Folder 1846)
        - "Questions and Discussion": typescript (Box 99, Folder 1847)
      - Audubon Society (Audubon Medal Acceptance: 1963 Dec): typescript, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1848)
      - Book and Author Luncheon Address (1951 Oct 16)
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1849)
        - Typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1850)
        - Related correspondence (with notes), 1951 Sep (Box 99, Folder 1851)
      - Congressional Hearings. "Statement of Rachel Carson Before the Subcommittee on Reorganization and Industrial Organizations of the Committee on Government Operations: Environmental Hazards. Control of Pesticides and Other Chemical Poisons" (1963 Jun 4)
        - Typescript, 1963 (Box 99, Folder 1852)
        - Federation of Homemakers reprint: typescript, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1853)
      - Cranbrook Institute of Science (1954 Apr 9): lectern typescript and carbon (Box 99, Folder 1854)
      - Drexel Institute of Technology. Commencement Address (1952 Jun 14): typescript, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1855)
      - Federation of Homemakers: lectern typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1856)
      - Garden Club of America (New York: 1963 Jan 8)
        - Holograph, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1857)
        - Typescripts, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1858-59)
        - Lectern typescript, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1860)
      - Garden Club of America (Philadelphia: 1963 May 9): typescript and photocopy (Box 99, Folder 1861)
      - Geographical Society of Philadelphia (1952 Jan): Acceptance of Henry G. Bryant Medal: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1862)
      - Houghton Mifflin Sales Conference Speech (1955 May): typescript, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1863)
      - International Council of Women (1963 Jun 19): typescript, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1864)
      - Kaiser Foundation ("Pollution of Our Environment") (1963 Oct 18-19)
        - Research material, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1865-72)
        - Notes, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1873)
        - Early drafts: holograph and typescript (Box 100, Folder 1874-75)
        - "Staff Notes for Restricted Distribution": preliminary copy with list of speeches, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1876)
        - Typescript (with introduction), n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1877)
        - Lectern typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1878)
        - Program, 1963 Oct 18-19 (Box 100, Folder 1879)
        - News clippings, 1963 Oct 19 (Box 100, Folder 1880)
        - Related correspondence, 1962-63 (Box 100, Folder 1881)
      - "Kennedy Group" Speech (on use of pesticides): typescript, [1962] (Box 101, Folder 1882)
      - National Book Award: typescript, 1952 (Box 101, Folder 1883)
      - National Council of Women (Book Award: 1956 Nov 27): typescripts and photocopy (Box 101, Folder 1884)
      - National Council of Women (1962 Oct 10)
        - Typescript, 1962 (Box 101, Folder 1885)
        - Lectern typescript, 1962 (Box 101, Folder 1886)
        - Program and publicity, 1962 (Box 101, Folder 1887)
      - National Parks Association (1962 Oct 10)
        - Holograph, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1888)
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1889)
      - National Symphony Luncheon (1951 Sep 25): lectern typescript, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1890)
      - National Wildlife Federation (Conservationist of the Year Award: 1963 Mar 2): typescript, photocopy, and mimeo (Box 101, Folder 1891)
      - New England Wildlife Preservation Society ("A Sense of Values in Today's World"): 1963 Jan 17)
        - Holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 101, Folder 1892-93)
        - Lectern typescript, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1894)
        - Printed copy, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1895)
      - New England Zoological Society (1953 Jan 14)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1896)
        - Lectern typescript, 1953 Jan 14 (Box 101, Folder 1897)
      - Quaint Acres Citizens Association (1959 Jun 11): typescript, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1898)
      - Rod and Gun Association (1963 Feb 21): typescript (with program and statement by Marie Rodell on Rachel Carson and Silent Spring ) (Box 101, Folder 1899)
      - Schweitzer Medal (Animal Welfare Institute: 1963 Jan 7)
        - Notes, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1900)
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1901)
      - Scripps College Commencement ("Of Man and the Stream of Time": 1962 Jun 12): typescript (Box 101, Folder 1902)
      - Special Libraries Association (1962 May 28): holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 101, Folder 1903)
      - Theta Sigma Phi ("The Real World Around Us": 1954 Apr 21"): typescript (Box 101, Folder 1904)
      - Women's National Book Association (Constance Skinner Award: 1963 Feb 15): typescript, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1905)
      - Women's National Press Club (1962 Dec 5)
        - Holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1906)
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1907)
        - Housewives Today (excerpt), 1963 Oct (Box 101, Folder 1908)
        - Newspaper clippings, 1963 (Box 101, Folder 1909)
        - Related correspondence, 1962 Nov 8 (Box 101, Folder 1910)
      - Unidentified Speeches
        - Speech to librarians, [1956?] (Box 101, Folder 1911)
        - Speech to women's group, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1912)
      - List of Rachel Carson's speeches (incomplete), n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1913)
      - List of Rachel Carson's speaking engagements, Sep 1962-Jan 1963 (Box 101, Folder 1914)
      - Miscellaneous fragments, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1915)
      - Miscellaneous clippings, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 1916)
- General Correspondence, 1942-73; Series II; 2.5; (5 boxes)
  Series II, General Correspondence, is arranged
  alphabetically. Correspondents with fewer than
  five letters have been placed in "letter" general
  files.
  - "A" general, 1953-63 (Box 102, Folder 1917)
  - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1951-53 (Box 102, Folder 1918)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters (National Institute of Arts & Letters), 1953-64 (Box 102, Folder 1919)
  - American Museum of Natural History
    See: Pough, Richard, Box 103 folder 1973
  - Anshen, Ruth Nanda (World Perspectives), 1952-63 (Box 102, Folder 1920)
    See also: Harper and Brothers, Boxes 103, folder 1951
  - "B" general, 1942-64 (Box 102, Folder 1921-22)
  - Babcock, Peggy, 1956, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 1923)
  - Baltimore Sun, 1936-64 (Box 102, Folder 1924)
  - Beston, Elizabeth Beston, Henry, 1954, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 1925)
  - Bigelow, Henry B., 1952-56 (Box 102, Folder 1926)
  - Bok, Curtis, 1955-56 (Box 102, Folder 1927)
  - Boynton, Mary Fuertes, 1949-51 (Box 102, Folder 1928)
  - Briggs, Shirley, 1946-56, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 1929)
  - "C" general, 1952-64 (Box 102, Folder 1930)
  - Carson, Maria, 1947-51, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 1931)
  - Carson, Robert, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 1932)
  - Cat Welfare Association of Columbus, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 1933)
  - Chatham College, 1959-64 (Box 102, Folder 1934)
  - Cottam, Clarence, 1959-64 (Box 102, Folder 1935-37)
  - Crile, George ("Barney"), 1960-69 (Box 102, Folder 1938)
  - Crisler, Lois, 1958-64 (Box 102, Folder 1939)
    Includes letter from Crisler to Marie [Rodell?], 1964 June 25
  - "D" general, 1951-64 (Box 102, Folder 1940)
  - "E" general, 1954-65 (Box 102, Folder 1941)
  - Eiseley, Loren C., 1960-64 (Box 102, Folder 1942)
  - "F" general, 1955-63, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 1943)
  - "G" general, 1952-63 (Box 102, Folder 1944)
  - Gimbel Brothers, 1951 (Box 102, Folder 1945)
  - Govan, Ada C., 1946-47 (Box 102, Folder 1946)
  - Gover, Nell H., 1954 (Box 102, Folder 1947)
  - Guggenheim Foundation (Box 102, Folder 1948)
  - "H" general, 1951-63 (Box 103, Folder 1949)
  - Halle Brothers Co., 1951 (Box 103, Folder 1950)
  - Harper and Brothers (Box 103, Folder 1951)
    See also: Ruth Nanda Anshen, Box 102, folder 1920
  - Harrison, Ruth, 1962-63 (Box 103, Folder 1952)
  - Harvey, E. Newton (Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute), 1955-59 (Box 103, Folder 1953)
  - "I-J-K" general, 1952-63 (Box 103, Folder 1954)
  - Kennedy, John F., 1960 (Box 103, Folder 1955)
  - Knecht, Beverly (with manuscript), 1958-59 (Box 103, Folder 1956-58)
  - "L" general, 1942-63 (Box 103, Folder 1959)
  - "M" general, 1948-69 (Box 103, Folder 1960-61)
  - McClain, Helena, 1956, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 1962)
  - Mangione, Jerre (University of Pennsylvania), 1963 (Box 103, Folder 1963)
  - Mayo Clinic (American Association for the Advancement of Science), 1963-64 (Box 103, Folder 1964)
  - Musical Masterpiece Society, 1956 (Box 103, Folder 1965)
  - "N" general, 1945-63 (Box 103, Folder 1966)
  - National Conference on Air Pollution, 1962 (Box 103, Folder 1967)
  - Nature Conservancy (with reports), 1953-57 (Box 103, Folder 1968)
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1951-56 (Box 103, Folder 1969)
  - New York Zoological Society, 1952-58 (Box 103, Folder 1970)
  - "O" general, 1946-62 (Box 103, Folder 1971)
  - "P" general, 1953-64 (Box 103, Folder 1972)
  - Pough, Richard, 1950-53 (Box 103, Folder 1973)
  - "R" general, 1951-64 (Box 104, Folder 1974)
  - Reader's Digest, 1945-55 (Box 104, Folder 1975)
  - Revelle, Roger, 1952, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 1976)
  - Rodell, Marie, 1948-58 (Box 104, Folder 1977-90)
  - Rodell, Marie, 1959-73, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 1991-95)
  - Rodell, Marie (Fuertes Project), 1949-51 (Box 105, Folder 1996)
  - Rodell, Marie (Condolences), 1964 (Box 105, Folder 1997)
    See also: Crisler, Lois
  - Rorty, James, 1963 (Box 105, Folder 1998)
  - Rose, Edith, 1956 (Box 105, Folder 1999)
  - Ruppertshofen, Heinz, 1963, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 2000)
  - "S" general, 1951-62 (Box 105, Folder 2001)
  - Schaefer, Vincent J. (Munitalp Foundation), 1956 (Box 105, Folder 2002)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr., 1958, 1962 (Box 105, Folder 2003)
  - Scripps College, 1953-62 (Box 105, Folder 2004)
  - Smith, Latrob, n.d. (Box 105, Folder 2005)